<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jbang | Kaoto - The Integration Designer for Apache Camel</title><link>https://kaoto.io/category/jbang/</link><atom:link href="https://kaoto.io/category/jbang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Jbang</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://kaoto.io/media/icon_hu28704772c4f249dcf6bfdf2e89e809cb_62841_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Jbang</title><link>https://kaoto.io/category/jbang/</link></image><item><title>Rapid Prototyping with Camel JBang and Kaoto</title><link>https://kaoto.io/portfolio/rapidprototypingjbang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://kaoto.io/portfolio/rapidprototypingjbang/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the following video we can see how to run your integration using Camel JBang dev mode.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls >
&lt;source src="https://kaoto.io/portfolio/rapidprototypingjbang/RapidPrototypingJBang.webm" type="video/webm">
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Please make sure you have the &lt;a href="https://camel.apache.org/manual/camel-jbang.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Camel JBang CLI&lt;/a> installed before you start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First we create a new route by selecting &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; in the top menu bar. Make sure that &amp;ldquo;Camel Route&amp;rdquo; is selected. This will already spawn a small integration which start with a &lt;strong>timer&lt;/strong> and ends with a &lt;strong>log&lt;/strong>. The timer is going to send a message to the following log step periodically. The log step will just log the message sent from the previous step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now hit the &lt;strong>Copy to Clipboard&lt;/strong> button in the top menu above your route visualization. This will copy the integration source code to your clipboard. We will use that in the next step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally we are going to run the integration in &lt;em>dev mode&lt;/em> from the clipboard. For this we open a console and enter the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">camel run clipboard.yaml --dev
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>We are using the &lt;a href="https://camel.apache.org/manual/camel-jbang.html#_run_from_clipboard" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Run from Clipboard&lt;/a> functionality of the Camel JBang CLI. This means whenever something is copied to your clipboard, it will automatically reloading in the Camel JBang CLI as the current integration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should by now see an output in the console repeating every second. You can now click on the &lt;strong>log&lt;/strong> step to open up the configuration form in Kaoto. Now scroll to the &lt;strong>Message&lt;/strong> property and change it to whatever you like to show up in the console. Finally hit again the &lt;strong>Copy to Clipboard&lt;/strong> button and watch the console reloading the integration and then your new message will show up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Please note, this is risky! For a more secure approach see &lt;a href="https://camel.apache.org/manual/camel-jbang.html#_dev_mode_with_live_reload" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dev Mode with Live Reload&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>